hello you're probably here to learn how
to program a g script too
and by at least i'm just going to try to
teach you at least the basics of it
and by the way you need to have a gold
dev or gold to program into script 2.
those are the subscription plans for
g-script
or we can grow online now first of all
you'll need to know how to
gain access to g-script too it's really
not
that easy you need pro server to program
on first
you need to look around for some servers
and have them hire you
or something or give you the rights to
enter it
so most of the servers listed here
won't let you work there unless you're
totally amazing at your script too
and that's not going to happen unless
you have practice which you need a
server to do
so you'll want to search for some
servers that are currently in
development
they'll at least some will hire you
i'll show you how to find all the
servers later
so we need two programs to
program in g-script two to do that go to
press start go to install packages
and download two things level editor
and remote control or this one
so level editing remote control a level
editor
is like a it's like an editor that lets
you create levels
and program in gscript one the thing is
about just
i'll go down to that later but you also
need remote control
so after downloading them you'll have to
go find them
so enter your graph folder which i'll
try to find in a second um
here it is find your graph folder
which is usually the c drive slash users
slash your name slash girl and
find and look around and you'll see girl
editor
and remote control 2 exe
so let's open girl editor
and you'll see some tiles some tiles at
the side you can put in
put on and all these buttons and whatnot
you can add the tiles if you want
and save the level and play it
or you can add npcs and program with
them
or program them to do whatever you want
so as i said earlier thing about
level editor compared to online
programming in growl is that the level
editor is in gscript
one the thing is about g skipped one
is that it's not nearly as flexible as
g-script 2.
you can't really do as much and all the
servers on girl
are going to be in gscript one if you if
they're not going to really hire you
unless you know just two because
g-script one is like a completely
different language
in their styles and syntax and
it's just useless to know if you're
trying to get hired on
a high class server so now
i'm gonna explain how to do this use
this later but i'm not going to save and
open remote control 2 or just remote
control
you'll see a login menu and you have to
log
in then you'll see all the servers on
girl
you'll have to look through them and oh
yeah
also if you have this you can type in
the name of the server here
and just enter it and see if they'll
hire you
usually the ones with large player
counts won't hire you
but the ones with lower player counts
will usually
now you'll want to find the server that
you have rights to
you know the one that you got hired on
or the one that you own
i own a server so i'm just gonna double
click that
it says i'm already logged in that's
because i logged in earlier
and here this is rc i'll show you how to
use it later
but yeah that concludes the first
tutorial
on how to program gscript 2. i haven't
really taught you
how to program yet but that'll be soon
if you can't understand how to download
the files or i don't know something
just comment below and i'll see if i can
reply
so anyway check out the next tutorial
when it's out
and probably will be by the time you see
this
and bye i guess